Contact

marina.gowid@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/marina-gowid-24235662 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Community Outreach Research Fast Learner

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Arabic (Limited Working)
Spanish (Elementary)

Certifications

CCRN (Adult)

Honors-Awards

Dean's List

Sigma Theta Tau International Honor Society of Nursing

Publications

Do you feel satisfied in your relationship: The role of compromise in satisfaction and commitment

Marina Gowid

Registered Nurse at Houston Methodist

Galveston, Texas

Summary

I am currently a Registered Nurse at Houston Methodist Hospital in the Cardiac Cath Lab. Previously, I worked for two years in the Cardiovascular ICU at Methodist.

I graduated with my Bachelor of Science in Nursing degree from The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston in December 2015. I have a Bachelor of Science degree from The University of Texas at Austin in Human Development and Family Sciences which was obtained in May 2013. I am very passionate about the medical field and my nursing interests lie in cardiovascular and critical care settings. I have healthcare experience and volunteer work in a variety of social and medical areas including clinics, nonprofit organizations, and hospitals.

Experience

Houston Methodist

4 years 4 months

Registered Nurse

March 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Cardiac Cath Lab.

Registered Nurse

February 2016 - February 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Houston, Texas Area

Cardiovascular Intensive Care Unit (CV ICU).

Registered Nurse

February 2016 - June 2017 (1 year 5 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Nurse Residency Program

Met on a weekly basis with other newly graduated nurses to facilitate the transition from school to work life.

Conducted EBP project regarding The Effect of Post-Transfer Visits on Patient Satisfaction HCAHPS scores in the Cardiovascular ICU.

Podium speaker at Nurse Residency graduation and presented results of unit based EBP project.

Houston Methodist

Student Nurse

October 2015 - November 2015 (2 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Capstone Internship (138 hrs) on Dunn 9 West Cardiac Intermediate Care Unit.

CHI St. Luke's Health

Student Nurse

September 2015 - October 2015 (2 months)

Adult III Critical Care Rotation (72 hrs) including Emergency Room, Cardiovascular Recovery Room (CVRR), Cooley 6A (Interventional Care), Cooley 7A (Progressive Care), and Cooley 8A (Transplant).

Memorial Hermann Health System

Student Nurse

June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months)

Obstetrics Clinical Rotation (72 hrs) including Antepartum (AP), Labor & Delivery (L&D), Postpartum (PP), Newborn Nursery (NBN), and Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU).

UTMB Community Health Program

Student Nurse

May 2015 - July 2015 (3 months)

Galveston, Texas

Community Rotation (30 hrs) including hospital and home visits with the Transitions of Care program with RN Stacy Avina.

Volunteering at St. Vincent's Clinic and Moody Day School (10 hrs)

Texas Children's Hospital

Student Nurse

May 2015 - June 2015 (2 months)

Pediatrics Clinical Rotation (72 hrs) including Progressive Care Unit (PCU), Pediatric Intensive Care Unit (PICU), Hematology/Oncology, and Emergency Care/Trauma.

Harris Health System

Student Nurse

March 2015 - April 2015 (2 months)

Ben Taub Hospital

Psychiatry Clinical Rotation (72 hrs) including inpatient floor, outpatient clinic, and pediatric clinic.

Houston Methodist

Student Nurse

January 2015 - February 2015 (2 months)

Adult II Medical Surgical Clinical Rotation (96 hrs) on Endocrinology and Nephrology Medical Surgical units.

UTMB

Student Nurse

September 2014 - December 2014 (4 months)

Galveston, Texas

Adult I Medical Surgical Clinical Rotation (96 hrs) including Acute Care for Elderly (ACE), Operating Room, and Medical Surgical units.

North Cypress Medical Center

Nurse Shadow

October 2013 - November 2013 (2 months)

North Cypress Medical Center

Shadowed Emergency Room RN Sherry Shenoda

Took patients' vital signs and transported lab specimen

Grace Care Center of Cypress

Nurse Aide Trainee

October 2013 - November 2013 (2 months)

Cypress, Texas

Provided nursing care to residents under supervision of preceptor

Care included assisting with feeding, dressing, and ambulatory needs

Page 3 of 5

Transported residents, took vital signs, and assisted with physical therapy

Helping Hand Home for Children Development Intern January 2013 - May 2013 (5 months)

Supported development team with donation processing through usage of The Raiser's Edge

Helped with organizing auction items and sending out invitations for The Crystal Ball Gala

Assisted with fundraising, marketing, and grant research

Worked with development coordinator on social media

The Daily Living Project
Research Assistant
May 2012 - May 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Completed Institutional Review Board (IRB) Human Subjects training

Developed and utilized a coding scheme for family members behaviors and interactions

Facilitated families completion of research questionnaires and problem solving activities

Presented original research at undergraduate research symposium

UTeach Outreach
Student Teacher
August 2010 - December 2010 (5 months)
Communicated with partner to create one-hour science lessons

Taught lessons to a class of 20 fourth graders once a week

Education

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston

Bachelor of Science (BS), Nursing · (2014 - 2015)

Lone Star College System (2008 - 2014)

The University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor of Science (BS), Human Development and Family Studies,

General · (2009 - 2013)

Universidad del País Vasco/Euskal Herriko Unibertsitatea Organic Chemistry · (2011 - 2011)